{
    "id": "549bf227746846af8e244707bbdac495",
    "title": "Subject-Verb Agreement",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He and his wife ……………………….. arrived.",
            "description": "Two or more singular nouns connected by and take a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Oil and water ……………………… not agree.",
            "description": "Two or more singular nouns connected by and take a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "does"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My mentor and benefactor ………………………. no more.",
            "description": "When two singular nouns refer to the same person, we use a singular verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The secretary and the chairman ……………………………. present at the meeting.",
            "description": "Here the articles used with the two nouns indicate that they refer to different people and hence we use a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Each person …………………………. a vote.",
            "description": "We use a singular noun and a singular verb after each.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Each day ………………………… its own challenges.",
            "description": "We use a singular noun and a singular verb after each.",
            "answers": [
                "bring",
                "brings"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither Rahul nor Rohan ………………………… passed the exam.",
            "description": "The verb is singular when two or more singular nouns are connected by nor.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Either Peter or James ………………………. left his umbrella in the classroom.",
            "description": "The verb is singular when two or more singular nouns are connected by or.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither the manager nor his personal assistants ……………………… there.",
            "description": "When the subjects joined by or or nor are of different number, the verb is plural. In this case, put the plural subject close to the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither he nor I ………………………… responsible for this.",
            "description": "When the subjects connected by or or nor are of different persons, the verb agrees in person with the nearest subject.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither you nor he ………………………… a good student.",
            "description": "When the subjects connected by or or nor are of different persons, the verb agrees in person with the nearest subject.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Everyone of them ……………………… there.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after every and everyone.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}